kellycareernetwork.com 2010-05-29

# | Kelly Services - Privacy Statement

Kelly Services, Inc. respects the privacy of our customers, applicants, and employees and we acknowledge that you have certain rights related to any personal information we collect from you. Kelly supports the various national and local privacy laws, and has procedures in place to meet the requirements of those laws.

The following information discloses our privacy principles in addition to our practices for gathering, storing, and using your personal data. We encourage you to review this information so that you may understand and consent to how we may collect, use, and share your personal information. Unless you provide sufficient personal information, we may be unable to assist you with your staffing or employment requirements.

  * **Our Commitment to Privacy**
  * **What Personal Data We Collect**
  * **Whom We Share It with**
  * **Choice: Opt Out/Opt In**
  * **Accuracy and Access**
  * **Security**
  * **How to Contact Us**

**Our Commitment to Privacy**

Kelly Services, Inc. is committed to maintaining the privacy and security of the personal information of our customers, applicants, and employees. Kelly’s privacy policies reflect these principles, and will also conform to any privacy requirements in the countries in which we do business. 

Top

**What** **Personal Data We Collect**

_Kelly informs our customers, applicants, and employees about the information we collect, how we use it, and whether it will be transferred to third parties. Where possible, we provide individuals with details prior to their providing information, or as soon thereafter as is practical._

Kelly Services' goal in collecting your personal data is to provide you with the most personalized service possible. By knowing more about you, Kelly Services is able to deliver leading staffing and employment services and, hence, a better service to you.

In general, personal information is requested when you contact us to look for employment or to search for a candidate to fill a job opening. We ask applicants for their names, addresses, and other personal information such as work experience, education, and skills. When hiring employees, we may also request personal information that is considered "sensitive," such as information necessary to provide health benefits. Kelly recommends that you do not disclose sensitive personal characteristics (e.g., gender.) on the initial resume or curriculum vitae (CV) you submit to us.

The amount of personal information you are required to supply will normally be limited to only that which is necessary to supply our services to you.

Applicants and Employees: When you sign up for our job-search services through the [Kelly Career Network™](http://www.kellycareernetwork.com/) (KCN™), we may ask you for your name, e-mail address, or other personal information such as work experience, education, and skills.

Our Preferred Candidate system includes a Personal Search Agent (PSA) that allows Web site visitors to create a job-search profile. The profile acts as an intelligent agent to identify those jobs in our database that match your criteria. When a matching job becomes available, our Preferred Candidate system will notify you. These e-mail notifications travel over the Internet via nonsecure networks.

We will also use your contact information to send you e-mail messages about our company or job postings that fit your profile. Only Kelly Services (or agents working on behalf of Kelly Services) will send you these direct mailings. You may opt out of receiving future mailings via e-mail; see the Choice: Opt Out/Opt In section below. At no time will we release your personal information to customers without your consent.

E-Learning Participants: For those who take advantage of Kelly’s e-learning courses, we may request an e-mail address from you and ask that you create a special password to access your courses, test scores, and course history. For those courses with training fees, Kelly may also collect credit card information.

E-Timekeeping for Temporary Employees: In order to process payroll for our temporary employees, Kelly may collect personal data online from our employees such as name, hours, address, and any other personal identification information, including a social security number or tax identification number. This data will be used to process payroll either through Kelly operations or an agent of Kelly Services. When collecting timekeeping data electronically or manually, Kelly Services will ensure that its collection and processing meets all privacy requirements.

Customers: For those customers who participate in any of Kelly’s various online procurement systems, we will ask for personal information necessary to fulfill the staffing request.

Cookies and Web Beacons: To help us provide better service, we sometimes collect anonymous information from visits to our sites through the use of "web beacons." These do not access your personal information, but rather allow Kelly to log users who have visited our Web sites. This anonymous information is sometimes known as "clickstream data." Kelly or its vendors may use this data to analyze trends and statistics to help us provide better customer service. If you do not want your transaction details used in this manner, see the paragraph below on cookies.

Many Kelly Web sites also use "cookies" to help personalize the online experience. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to information about that user. They also allow us to identify those computers when they return to a site. You can set your browser to notify you before you receive a cookie, giving you the option of whether to accept it. You can also set your browser to turn off cookies. If you do so, however, areas of some sites may not function properly. Kelly uses both session ID and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie simply terminates once users close the browser. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user’s hard drive for an extended period of time. These can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions.

Links: This Web site contains links to other Kelly sites that adhere to the same privacy principles. For links to non-Kelly organizations, Kelly Services is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.  

Retention of Personal Data: Personal data that is collected from you will be retained or destroyed according to company requirements and/or local laws.

Top  

**Whom We Share It with**

_Kelly holds its employees, agents, and suppliers accountable for maintaining the trust our applicants, employees, and customers place in us. We educate our employees and periodically verify our compliance with our privacy and security policies. Kelly does not sell or trade personal data to third parties. We will disclose personal information when required by law._

In order to provide our services, personal data you give us may be shared with other Kelly operations that are governed by the same privacy principles and security practices. Because of the global scope of our operation, this data may also be transferred, stored, and processed in the United States or any other country in which Kelly or its affiliates, subsidiaries, or agents maintain facilities.

We will send the personal data of our applicants and temporary employees to Kelly customers and/or agents who are acting on our behalf to provide you an employment opportunity.

For our employees, we occasionally use other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as payroll processing services and health-care benefits.

We may also send your personal data to marketing companies who will then contact you to determine your feedback and satisfaction with our services. These companies may also send you information on our services.

We will only provide these agents and suppliers with the personal information they need to deliver the service we have requested.

Kelly Services may also collect and report demographic data, (e.g. what percentage of our employees are college graduates) to customers, marketing companies, or as required by law. If we do collect and report this demographic information, we remove any unique personally identifiable information (name, address, etc.) that would attach you to this demographic data. This anonymous information is used and analyzed only at an aggregate level to help us understand trends and more precisely determine how to improve our services to you.

The jobs portion of the Kelly Services (US Only) website is powered by Monster. When you submit registration information and/or your resume, your information and your resume are hosted on a segregated area of Monster's servers. If you apply for a job or elect to activate your resume at Kelly Career Network, Kelly Services will be able to view your information and your resume, but no one else will be able to view them. In the future, if you visit Monster's website or another website whose careers area is powered by Monster, you may be invited to activate your resume there as well. Only those websites on which you activate your resume will be able to view your information and your resume. Moreover, if you activate your resume on Monster's website, such activation will be treated as if you had originally registered with Monster and posted your resume in its searchable database for viewing and downloading by Monster's employer and agency Customers. In such case, Monster's handling of your registration information and your resume will be subject to Monster's Privacy Statement, which can be found by clicking the link entitled "Monster.com Privacy Statement" at the bottom of the Monster.com homepage.

Top  

**Choice: Opt Out/Opt In**

_Kelly offers its customers, applicants, and employees choices about receiving further communications from us, uses of information beyond the purposes for which it was provided, and transferring data to third parties. Kelly obtains consent for any information deemed sensitive._

The amount of personal information you are required to supply will normally be limited to that which is necessary to supply the services you requested. For users of our [Kelly Career Network™](http://www.kellycareernetwork.com/) (KCN™), we may periodically send you updates via e-mail to alert you to jobs in our database that match your criteria. We may also send you e-mails regarding other career or promotional opportunities. Each notification tells you how to opt out of receiving future e-mails. At the point where we request personal data about you, our site also gives you the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications. The database is automatically updated when you opt out.

Sensitive Data - Opt In: When hiring employees, Kelly may collect the type of data viewed by some countries as "sensitive," such as information required to provide health-care services. This collection of data is either compatible with employment law or is vital to the interests of the Kelly employee. In order to comply with statutes, rules and regulations pertaining to equal employment opportunities or to assist Kelly in compiling data for its affirmative action practices, we may also ask you to provide gender or racial information. This provision of this type of information will be voluntary, unless it is required by law, and will not hinder your employment opportunities. When collecting sensitive information, we will ask you to provide your consent to collect, store, and in some cases, transfer this data to third parties including payroll service companies, health insurance organizations, or government agencies as required by law. Kelly takes all reasonable security measures to protect the confidentiality and integrity of sensitive data collected, stored, and used.

Top  

**Accuracy and Access**

_Kelly takes the necessary steps to ensure personal information is accurate, complete, and current. Kelly provides individuals with reasonable access to the personal information they have provided so that they can review and correct this information._

Kelly strives to keep your personally identifiable information accurate. We will give you the ability to review and update the personal information you have provided. Because Kelly offers a wide variety of different services through a global network, the personal information collected by each Kelly operation may not all reside in a single location, such as when you submit your résumé/curriculum vitae (CV) to Kelly operations in different countries. Consequently, please be aware that the choices and modifications you make to your personal data in one Kelly operation may not automatically be reflected in other Kelly operations. You may therefore need to contact each Kelly operation to learn how to access and update your information. (See the How to Contact Us section below.)

At this site, you may access and change your own personal data at any time by going to the [Kelly Career Network](http://www.kellycareernetwork.com/)™ (KCN™) page, entering your last name and e-mail address in the supplied fields, and selecting "Edit My Registration."

There are no fees associated with accessing or updating the personal data previously provided by you.

Top  

**Security**

_Kelly takes care to secure personal information given to us by our customers, applicants, and employees. We protect this personal information through various security practices and measures in order to prevent loss, misuse, alteration, unauthorized access, destruction, or disclosure._

Kelly Services protects the security of the personal information you provide. This information may be stored in manual or electronic systems with limited access in order to protect this information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

Top  

**How to Contact Us**

_Kelly provides a way to respond to your privacy questions or handle your disputes. We assign ownership of our data privacy practices at both the local and U.S. world headquarters level to provide open communication and dispute resolution to our customers, applicants, and employees. Kelly abides by the "Safe Harbor" framework developed by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Commission. We will fully cooperate with the Federal Trade Commission or local data protection authorities when requested to do so._

At Kelly, we are working hard to protect your privacy while delivering innovative career development and staffing services. Our privacy principles represent our commitment to ensuring that your personal information is safe and secure. If you believe that Kelly has not adhered to these principles and practices, contact us and we will work diligently to promptly determine and remedy the problem.

Kelly World Headquarters (Michigan, USA)
